MELVYN THOMAS WILLIAM LING

MELVYN.LING@GMAIL.COM | 289 788 2149 | HAMILTON, ONTARIO L8L 2L6 LINKEDIN.CA/MELVYN-LING | GITHUB.COM/MELVYNLING | MELVYNLING.GITHUB.IO/PORTFOLIO

SUMMARY

A front-end web developer whose creative flair and adaptive nature strike the balance between form and function. As a recent graduate of the University of Toronto's School of Continuing Studies Web Development program, a strong command of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Node.js, MongoDB, and MySQL has been established. He uses his diverse experience to optimise and contextualise his projects to best serve their target demographics. A superb communicator, with over 6 years experience in a customer service role and over 2 years of experience in sales/account management environment. His passions include learning, beating personal bests, functional design, and all things JavaScript. Actively, he is pursuing knowledge in Python, Blockchain, Angular, and TypeScript

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML/CSS

jQuery

JavaScript

- Node.js
- React.js
- Handlebars.js
- MERN Stack
- API/AJAX
- Google Firebase
- Version Control (GitHub)
- MySQL/MongoDB
- Heroku

PROJECTS

cryptoTRKR Lead Developer

github.com/MelvynLing/cryptoTRKR cryptotrkr.herokuapp.com

• This app allows the user to see the historical data of their favourite 4 cryptocurrencies. It is a serverless Reactapp that stores the user's selection in their browser's localStorage. It also utilizes React Context API to make the API calls to the CryptoCompare API.

Technology used: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, NodeJS, Lodash, MomentsJS, highchartsJS, CryptoCompare API, React, localStorage

BitCoin Value Tracker Team Developer

github.com/MelvynLing/bitCoinValueTracker | gentle-spire-69297.herokuapp.com

• This application allows the users to see the historical trends of Bitcoin. The user enters entry and exit dates for potential bitcoin investments and is shown how profitable they could have been. I was responsible for the API call, the math and logic involved with calculating the rates, as well as the overall appearance of the application.

Techs used: HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, NodeJS, MomentsJS, handlebarsJS, coindesk API, Materialize UI, MySQL

Train Scheduler Lead Developer

github.com/MelvynLing/trainscheduler | melvynling.github.io/trainscheduler

• This app allows the user to create a train schedule, allowing them to see their trains arrival and departure times. This is a serverless application - utilizing google Firebase to store the user's inputs instead of a standard database.

Techs used: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, Bootstrap,

West Ham United App Lead Developer

github.com/MelvynLing/whuapp westhamapp.herokuapp.com/

• This is an app that allows the owner to show a sports team's recent schedule, as well as their most current roster, as well as take in inputs for a promotion. The owner can then log in and add/edit players to the roster and add/edit games to the schedule. Google Firebase was used for the database in this application

Techs used: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Firebase, React, Material UI, d3

EXPERIENCE

Operations Assistant (Part-Time)

Alco Sheet Metal Inc.

(Intermittently) April 2012 – Present Hamilton, Ontario

- Supported managers, tradespeople, and all others in the daily operations of the company, assisting with data entry and I.T. related activities, as well as in the tool shop and on various jobsites on an as needed basis.
- Provided essential software support; Facilitated training for two colleagues on new computer programs and operating systems, advised in the selection of programs for managers.
- Demonstrated excellent communication skills by relying pertinent information received via email or telephone to their intended parties.

Customer Service Representative

May 2016 – December 2018 Burlington, Ontario

OSG Canada Inc.

- Responsible for answering technical questions regarding products, customer service duties, order entry, quoting specialized tools, daily sales reporting, daily purchasing, customs paperwork, as well as receiving and preparing of tools for coating.
- Gained sales and account management experience by working the order desk; upselling customers to products that best suited their applications when necessary.
- Escalated inquiries to the appropriate department when necessary to ensure customer satisfaction, debriefing necessary individuals/departments when needed.

Automobile Claims Advisor/Disposition Advisor

September 2013 – October 2014

Aviva Canada Inc.

Hamilton, Ontario

- Worked as a front-line agent, set up automobile insurance claims for customers who had been involved in an automobile accident via phone or email.
- Diligently entered claim and customer information into several computer systems, both web and DOS based, to ensure all necessary information was needed for anyone to handle the claim if necessary.
- Used strong communication skills and courteous phone etiquette in order to explain fault determinations and insurance coverages to customers, as well as pass on information to other advisors.

EDUCATION

School of Continuing Studies, Full-Stack Web Development Certificate

December 2018 University of Toronto

- Toronto, Ontario

Bachelor of Arts (Honours), Political Science.

Hamilton, Ontario

April 2012 McMaster University